https://www.nsf.org/privacy-copyright

Client Login
Language:
Home
Looking for certified products and systems instead?
Privacy and Copyright
Welcome to the NSF International website (www.nsf.org). Please read the following information regarding privacy, security, terms and conditions as they govern your access to and use of this site. By accessing, viewing and using the NSF International website, you agree to abide by these policies, terms and conditions.
Site and Program Ownership
This site is owned and operated by NSF International (NSF). Our
principal office is located at 789 North Dixboro Road, Ann Arbor, MI
48105, USA.
Copyright
Copyright © 1996-2020 NSF International. All rights reserved. All
text, images, graphics and other materials on this site are subject to
the copyrights and other intellectual property rights of NSF
International. NSF International owns the copyrights in the selection,
coordination and arrangement of the materials on this site. These
materials may not be copied for commercial use or distribution, nor may
these materials be modified or reposted to other sites, without the
prior express written permission of NSF International.
Privacy and Website Usage Data
At NSF International, we strive to honor the privacy and security of
our users, customers and suppliers, as well as their representatives, in
relation to all products, services, applications and websites provided
by NSF International, 789 North Dixboro Rd, Ann Arbor, MI 48105 USA ) or
its affiliates (each an NSF entity and collectively NSF or we/us hereunder).
This privacy statement describes the types of information we may
collect from you or that you may provide to us, for instance when you
visit the websites owned or operated by us (including but not limited to
www.nsf.org; collectively the "Websites"), and our
practices for collecting, using, maintaining, protecting, and disclosing
that information. Please read this privacy statement carefully in order
to understand our policies and practices regarding your information and
how we will treat it.
This privacy statement may change from time to time. Please check for
updates. If you have any questions or comments regarding this privacy
statement, please contact us at data.protection@nsf.org.
Personal Data
Children Under the Age of 13
Our Websites are not intended for children under 13 years of age. We
do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13.
If you are under 13, do not use or provide any information on our
Websites or provide any information about yourself to us, including your
name, address, telephone number, email address, or any screen name or
user name you may use. If we learn we have collected or received
personal information from a child under 13 without verification of
parental consent (to the extent such consent is required), we will
delete that information. If you believe we might have any information
from or about a child under 13, please contact us at our Data Protection
team: NSF International, 789 N. Dixboro Road, Ann Arbor MI 48105 or via
email at data.protection@nsf.org.
Kinds of Personal Data Processed
When you submit a request or electronically pass information to any
NSF entity (including, but not limited to, orders, subscriptions,
registration, contest or survey participations, comments, feedback,
forms, transactions, employment applications and resumes), you are
sometimes asked to provide certain information, including, but not
limited to, your name, title, company, address, phone and fax numbers,
e-mail address and line of business, as well as appropriate categories
of personal data (such as transactional data in the event of
transactions). When you browse on any of our Websites, we may also
automatically collect electronic identification and configuration data,
such as device- or connection-related details. These kinds of data will
in many circumstances be considered as personal data under applicable
data protection legislation.
In addition to obtaining personal data from you or your device
directly, we may obtain such personal data from third parties, for
example our business partners.
For more information on the automated collection of information
through cookies and similar files/tags, please see our section below on
Cookies.
Purposes of Processing
We use information that we collect about you or that you provide to us, including any personal data:
Based on our legitimate interest in promoting our services:
To present our services, our Websites and their contents to you.
To notify you about changes to our Websites or any products or services we offer or provide though it.
Based on a (potential) contract with you or our legitimate interest in concluding or performing a contract with your employer:
To provide you with information, products, or services that you request from us.
To fulfill any other purpose for which you provide it.
To carry out our obligations and enforce our rights arising from
any contracts entered into between you and us, including for billing and
collection.
For any other purpose with your consent.
The information we collect automatically is statistical data and
does not/may include personal data , but we may maintain it or associate
it with personal data we collect in other ways or receive from third
parties. It helps us to improve our Websites and to deliver a better and
more personalized service, including by enabling us to:
Recognize you when you return to our Websites.
Speed up your searches.
Estimate our audience size and usage patterns.
Store information about your preferences (mailing lists you've
signed up for, services your company is interested in), which allows us
to customize our Websites according to your individual interests.
We may also use your information to contact you about our own
services that may be of interest to you. If you do not want us to use
your information in this way, see Your Rights as a Data Subject.
Disclosure of Your Personal Data
We may disclose aggregated information about our users and
information that does not identify any individual, without restriction.
We may disclose personal data that we collect or you provide as
described in this privacy statement:
To our subsidiaries and affiliates for the purpose of delivering the service for which you provided it.
To contractors, service providers, and other third parties we use
to support our business and who are bound by contractual obligations to
keep personal information confidential and use it only for the purposes
for which we disclose it to them.
To a buyer or other successor in the event of a merger,
divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, or other sale
or transfer of some or all of NSF's assets, whether as a going concern
or as part of bankruptcy, liquidation, or similar proceeding, in which
personal information held by NSF about our Website users is among the
assets transferred.
To fulfill the purpose for which you provide it.
For any other purpose disclosed by us when you provide the information.
With your consent.
We may also disclose your personal data:
To comply with any court order, law, or legal process, including to respond to any government or regulatory request.
To enforce or apply our terms of use or terms of and other agreements, including for billing and collection purposes.
If we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to protect
the rights, property, or safety of NSF, our customers, or others.
International Data Transfers
In the event of transfer of personal data from (initially from a
country within the European Economic Area to another country outside of
the European Economic Area, NSF systematically ensures the application
of an adequate level of protection of such personal data by approved
means (e.g. selecting "Privacy Shield"-certified processors or putting
in place standard contractual clauses on the processing of personal
data, in accordance with the EU Commission model clauses). You can
request more information about such measures (including copies where
relevant) by getting in touch with NSF through the contact details
below.
Your Rights as a Data Subject
Subject to applicable law, you may have some or all of the following
rights in respect of your personal data. You can exercise these rights
by submitting your request [by getting in touch with NSF at
data.protection@nsf.org. Please include your personal details as well as
some means of verifying your identity (e.g. copy of identity card.).
Please note that NSF may reject requests that are excessive or a misuse of the relevant right.
Access right: You may have the right to obtain
confirmation of whether NSF processes personal data in relation to you
and, if so, gain access to a copy thereof. For certain kinds of data,
you may also have a right to data portability.
Data accuracy: right of rectification and right to
erasure. You may have the possibility rectify or obtain the erasure of
your personal data, provided that the applicable legal requirements are
met. The right to erasure is subject to various exceptions, notably as
regards personal data whose processing is necessary to support
litigation or for compliance with statutory retention requirements.
Please note that it may not always be possible for us to delete
your personal data on the relevant Website without deleting your user
account.
Limits to processing: right to restriction, right
to object and consent withdrawal. In addition, you may have the right to
object to the processing of personal data based on NSF's legitimate
interests (see above) and to otherwise obtain the restriction of certain
forms of processing in specific circumstances. In particular, in
relation to the processing of personal data for direct marketing
purposes, you may have the right to object at any time thereto. Where
any processing is based on consent, you may have the right to withdrawal
such consent at any time (without this affecting the processing prior
to the consent withdrawal).
You can exercise this right sending us an email stating your
request to data.protection@nsf.org. If we have sent you a promotional
email, you may click on the unsubscribe box at the bottom of the email
which will omit you from future email distributions. [This opt-out does
not apply to the processing of personal data in the context of a service
purchase, warranty registration, service experience or other
transactions.]
In relation to cookies and tracking technologies, you can set your
browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when
cookies are being sent. To learn how you can manage your cookie
settings, visit your browser settings. If you disable or refuse all
cookies, including functional cookies, please note that some parts of
this site may then be inaccessible or not function properly.
Right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authorities:
You may have the right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory
authority, in particular the data protection authority that is competent
for your place of residence.
Your California Privacy Rights
California Civil Code Section § 1798.83 permits users of our
Websites that are California residents to request certain information
regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for
their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an
email to data.protection@nsf.org, or write us at Data Protection Team,
NSF International,789 North Dixboro Road, Ann Arbor, MI 48105.
Data Security
We have implemented measures designed to secure your personal data
from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, alteration, and
disclosure. The safety and security of your data also depends on you.
Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password for access
to certain parts of our Websites, you are responsible for keeping this
password confidential. We ask you not to share your password with
anyone.
Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is
not completely secure. Although we do our best to protect your personal
data, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal data transmitted
to our Websites. Any transmission of personal data is at your own risk.
We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or
security measures contained on the Websites.
Cookies
General principles regarding the use of cookies and other files/tags
Our Websites use cookies, pixel tags and other forms of
identification and local storage (together referred to as "tags/files"
hereunder) to distinguish you from other users of our Websites. This
helps us provide you with a good experience when you browse our Websites
and also allows us to improve our Websites and our services.
In many cases, these tags/files lead to the use of your device's
processing or storage capabilities. Some of these tags/files are set by
NSF itself, others by third parties; some only last as long as your
browser session, while others can stay active on your device for a
longer period of time.
In particular, the technologies we use for automatic data collection may include:
Cookies (or browser cookies). A cookie is a small
file placed on the hard drive of your computer. You may refuse to
accept browser cookies by activating the appropriate setting on your
browser. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access
certain parts of our Websites. Unless you have adjusted your browser
setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies
when you direct your browser to our Websites.
Flash Cookies. Certain features of our Websites
may use local stored objects (or Flash cookies) to collect and store
information about your preferences and navigation to, from, and on our
Websites. Flash cookies are not managed by the same browser settings as
are used for browser cookies.
Web Beacons. Pages of our Websites and our
e-mails may contain small electronic files known as web beacons (also
referred to as clear gifs, pixel tags, and single-pixel gifs) that
permit NSF, for example, to count users who have visited those pages or
opened an email and for other related website statistics (for example,
recording the popularity of certain website content and verifying system
and server integrity).
For information about managing your privacy and security settings for cookies, see Your Rights as a Data Subject.
These tags/files can fall into several categories: (i) those that
are necessary for functionality or services that you request or for the
transmission of communications (functionality tags/files); (ii) those
that we use to carry out performance and audience metrics regarding our
website (analytics tags/files) and (iii) the rest (tracking across a
network of other websites, advertising, etc.) (other tags/files).
Depending on applicable law, different rules may apply. Within the
European Union, for instance, functionality and analytical tags/files do
not require your consent. For analytical and other tags/files, however,
we request your consent before placing them on your device. You can
give your consent by allowing cookies in your browser settings, by
continuing to use our website, or by clicking on the appropriate button
on the banner displayed to you.
Cookie Settings
You can find more information about cookies and similar tags/files at the following addresses:
www.allaboutcookies.org
www.youronlinechoices.eu (a guide to behavioral advertising and online privacy, produced by the internet advertising industry)
Specific information relating to this website
We use the following cookies on this website specifically:
NSF Essential (Functional) Cookies: Enables you to navigate the
site and use it's services and features. We also use preference cookies
to collect information about your choices and preferences (for example,
language and location settings).
Tracking Cookies, such as Pardot, etc.: Allow us to assess how you
and other web users use this website, and this information is essential
in helping us to continuously improve our website's functionality. They
can be preserved from 30 minutes to 2 years. Also enable us to follow
up on your request for information about specific services and help us
remember preferences (like form field values) when you return to our
site. (Pardot cookies don't store personally identifying information,
only a unique identifier.)
Changes we make to our privacy statement will be made public on this
page with a notice, on the relevant Website home page, stating that the
privacy statement has been updated. If we make material changes to how
we treat our users' personal data, we will notify through a notice to
your primary email address or on the relevant Website home page. The
date the privacy statement was last revised is identified at the bottom
of the page. You are responsible for periodically visiting our Websites
and this privacy statement to check for any changes.
Contact Information
To ask questions or comment about this privacy statement and our
privacy practices, contact us at: Data Protection Team, NSF
International, 789 N. Dixboro Road, Ann Arbor MI 48105 or via email at
data.protection@nsf.org or by calling us at: 800-NSF-MARK (800-673-6275
(toll-free in USA) or (+1) 734-769-8010.
Last Modified: May 22, 2018
User Names, Passwords and Security
Some sections of the NSF International website (NSF Connect) require
the use of a user name and password. When you use this site, you are
encouraged to maintain the confidentiality of your user name and
password as you will be responsible for all the activities that occur
under your user name or password. We also remind you that you should
monitor the usage of your NSF website user names and passwords by your
employees. You are free, at any time, to request a change in your user
name and password. You can do this by contacting your project manager.
When needed, we do reserve the right to refuse service, terminate
accounts, remove or edit content, or cancel transactions. NSF takes
reasonable precautions to protect the security of the information.
Links to Third-Party Sites
This website may contain links to third-party sites. When you click
on a link, you may leave our site. Access to any other Internet site
linked to this website is at the user's own risk. NSF is not responsible
for the accuracy or reliability of any information, data, opinions,
advice or statements made on those sites. We encourage you to read their
terms and conditions, terms of use, privacy policies and/or privacy
statements prior to using their site, as NSF is not responsible for the
privacy policies of other sites. NSF International provides these links
merely as a convenience and the inclusion of such links does not imply
an endorsement.
Trademarks, Copyrights and Other Intellectual Property Rights
All content included or available on this site, including the site's
design, code, text, graphics, interfaces and the selection and
arrangements thereof, is proprietary to NSF and is copyrighted by NSF
with all rights reserved, or is the property of third parties protected
by intellectual property rights. Any use of materials on this site,
including reproduction for purposes expressly permitted in these terms
and conditions, modification, distribution, replication, any form of
data extraction or data mining, or other commercial exploitation of any
kind, without prior written permission of NSF is strictly prohibited.
Pages containing social media bookmarks for sharing, such as NSF news
releases and fact sheets, are permitted to be shared in their entirety
via these tools. All copies of data from this site must retain all
copyright and other proprietary notices. You agree that all of NSF's
trademarks, certificate marks, trade names, service marks and other
logos and brands (collectively, the "NSF marks") are the exclusive
property of NSF and you shall not display or use any NSF marks in any
manner without the prior written consent of NSF.
Disclaimer of Warranties and Limitation of Liability
This site is provided by NSF International on an "AS IS"; and "AS
AVAILABLE" basis. NSF International makes no representations or
warranties of any kind, express or implied, as to the operation of this
site or the information, content, materials or products included on this
site. You expressly agree that your use of this site is at your sole
risk. To the full extent permissible by applicable law, NSF
International disclaims all warranties, express or implied, including,
but not limited to, implied warranties of merchantability and fitness
for a particular purpose. NSF International does not warrant that this
site, its servers or email sent from NSF International are free of
viruses or other harmful components. NSF International will not be
liable for any damages of any kind arising from the use of this site,
including, but not limited to direct, indirect, incidental, punitive and
consequential damages.
Changes: We may change this privacy policy at any
time. If we make changes to this privacy policy, we will notify you by
publication on this page.
Applicable Law
By visiting NSF International's site, you agree that the laws of the
state of Michigan, without regard to principles of conflicts of laws,
will govern these website terms of use and any dispute of any sort that
might arise between you and NSF International.
We can be reached at info@nsf.org, 800-NSF-MARK (800-673-6275) or (+1) 734-769-8010.
Our postal address is:
P.O. Box 130140,
789 North Dixboro Road,
Ann Arbor, MI 48113-0140, USA
